psav.com 2013-05-23

# Privacy | PSAV

## How We Protect Your Privacy

The privacy and security of your personal information is very important to us. We do not share your personal information in ways not disclosed in our privacy policy or without your informed permission. We value your trust highly, and strive to protect the confidentiality and appropriate use of any personal information you provide to us. Details are described below.

PSAV Presentation Services complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. psav.com participates in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should contact us (as provided above).

If there are questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact: 

**PSAV Presentation Services**  
Attn: Privacy Office  
111 West Ocean Boulevard  
Suite 1110  
Long Beach, California 90802   
Phone: 1-562-366-0621  
Fax: 1-562-366-0628  
Email: [privacyoffice@psav.com](mailto:privacyoffice@psav.com)

### Privacy Policy

Purpose of this Privacy Policy  
Personally Identifiable Information PSAV Collects and Uses  
Personally Identifiable Information Disclosure  
Web site and Internet Privacy  
Links to Other Websites  
Active Information Collection  
Passive Information Collection  
Other Uses and Disclosures of Information  
Data Security  
How to Opt Out of Receiving Marketing Materials from PSAV  
Ask Us / Enforcement of this Privacy Policy  
Changes to this Privacy Policy  
Acceptance of this Privacy Policy

This is the Audio Visual Services Group, Inc. (doing business as PSAV Presentation Services (“PSAV”)) privacy policy.

#### Purpose of this Privacy Policy

PSAV recognizes the importance of protecting your personally identifiable information (such as your name, phone number, email address and other contact information, collectively, “PII”) that you provide to PSAV. This Privacy Policy sets forth our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of your PII both through our online and offline operations. This Privacy Policy also explains how you can correct or change the PII we hold about you, or opt out of receiving certain marketing materials.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to tell you how PSAV strives to better serve you by keeping you informed of promotions, products and services, while, at the same time, safeguarding your PII.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and part of, the Terms of Use, which govern PSAV’s Web sites (the “PSAV Sites”).

#### Personally Identifiable Information PSAV Collects and Uses

When you order equipment or service and/or join one of PSAV’s programs, we need to collect certain information about you in order to provide and improve our services. The service that you chose will determine what information we collect from you. This information may include, but not be limited to:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Home and/or business address
  * Phone numbers at which we can contact you
  * Your date of birth
  * Method of payments (credit card and expiration date)
  * Driver’s license and province/country of issuance

When you order equipment or service, we will also record information that details your order (e.g. where you ordered the equipment or service, where and when you used the equipment or service, payment arrangements, insurance preferences and other information related to the equipment or service personnel).

We may also need certain information from you when you request any of the following services or equipment: Special Needs/Optional Equipment; Special Offers/Discounts; Partner Member Numbers; use of a PSAV Corporate Discount code. For example, if you wish to use a discount that PSAV provides to members of an association/affiliate to which you belong, we may collect information about your membership to verify and provide you with the correct discount for our services.

How we collect this information will depend on how you use our services. We may collect this information directly from you by postal mail, phone, fax, email, at our offices, upon completion of an application or enrollment form, or through your use of our PSAV Sites or the Internet. To the extent you use our PSAV Sites, we may also collect information about your use of our PSAV Sites, transactional and account information, email and other information related to communications to our PSAV Sites. We may also collect information about you indirectly through a travel agent, an account program in which you or your employer participates or through one of our partner programs when you deal with us through those means. Additionally, our affiliates and third parties may provide us with information about you.

You may choose not to provide some of your PII to us, but this may prevent us from providing our services to you, or limit our ability to provide you with the level of service that you would otherwise expect from us.

#### Personally Identifiable Information Disclosure

##### _Usage_

We strive to ensure that we give you a stress-free experience and are dedicated to building a rewarding and lasting relationship with every customer. In order to provide the level of service we believe you expect from us, we may use your PII for the following purposes:

  * To provide the services and offerings that you request, and to communicate with you regarding such services and offerings;
  * To do all things necessary to administer those services;
  * To research, develop, manage, protect and improve our PSAV Sites and services;
  * To maintain and develop our service-oriented software and other business systems; and
  * To analyze data, or to have a third party do so on our behalf.

We also use your PII information or some discrete part such as your email address for other purposes. If you use our PSAV Sites, information may also be used to evaluate what portions of our PSAV Sites are visited more often than others, determine where visitors came from, where they go, and how long they stay on a particular page, or on the PSAV Sites in general.

We may match information collected from you through different means or at different times, including, for example, information collected online and offline, and use such information along with information obtained from other sources, including third parties.

To do this, it is often necessary to share this information with carefully selected vendors and business partners we work with, such as companies that manage accounts, offer affinity, frequent-user, and reward programs, and companies that perform marketing services and other business operations for us. For more information see Disclosing below.

##### _Disclosing_

We may disclose your PII to affiliated and non-affiliated organizations including, for example:

  * To your company or organization if you use our services under a corporate or other commercial account;
  * To entities that provide services on our behalf;
  * To your credit card issuer;
  * To credit reporting and fraud checking agencies; To debt collection agencies, if you fail to pay monies owed to us;
  *  To government, regulatory and law enforcement agencies where the disclosure is required or authorized by law, and otherwise as we believe is necessary or appropriate to satisfy any law, regulation or other governmental request, to operate our PSAV Sites properly, or to protect or defend our rights or the or rights well-being of our employees, users or others or if you are involved (or are suspected by governmental authorities or our security functions to be involved) in any illegal activity, even without a subpoena, warrant or court order.

If you come to our site through an affiliate, we may also disclose your information to our affiliates and non-affiliated business partners for their use both on our behalf and for their own business purposes. You may opt-out of us disclosing your PII for these purposes through one of the methods described below.

We may also share your information with other non-affiliated third parties, such as entities that provide services for or through our PSAV Sites or for our business (e.g., advertisers, ad servers, content providers, services providers, credit card processors, fulfillment services providers, email list hosting companies and distribution companies) that use such information on our behalf consistent with this Privacy Policy. These types of third parties are not permitted to use your information for any secondary purposes.

We may also transfer or assign your information to third parties as a result of or in connection with a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of assets, reorganization or liquidation.

#### Web site and Internet Privacy

If you use our PSAV Sites or otherwise interact with us via the Internet, the following privacy-related policies also apply:

#### Links to Other Websites

Our Site may contain links or references to other Web sites outside of our control, and the privacy policies of these sites may differ from our own. Please be aware that we have no control over such Web sites and our privacy policy does not apply to such Web sites. We advise you to check the privacy policies of such sites before disclosing any PII via such sites.

#### Active Information Collection

At various points on the PSAV Sites, you might choose to actively provide certain kinds of information, including personally identifiable information, such as full name, address, phone number, email address, etc. The Site typically will indicate which information is required and which information is optional at the information collection point in question. In any case, by submitting information via an active information collection point at any of the PSAV Sites, you specifically consent to the collection, use, and dissemination of such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Active information collection points at this Site may include:

##### Online Transactions

PSAV maintains rigorous standards to protect your personal information. We use encryption technology to ensure the secure transmission of any personal information you provide for use during an onsite transaction. All transactions at our site are conducted using 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption. SSL is the standard security technology for establishing an encrypted link between a Web server and a Web browser. This link ensures that all data passed between the Web server and browsers remain private and integral. SSL s an industry standard and is used by millions of Web sites in the protection of online transactions with customers. You can easily determine when you are sending data securely by looking at the Web address (URL) in your browser window: the first few letters will change, from “http” to “https” when you are transmitting information protected by SSL encryption. The “s” in “https” stands for “secure.”  

##### Email Reply Mechanisms

The PSAV Sites may provide you with one or more email mechanisms through which you may submit questions or comments. Information you provide via such email mechanisms is typically optional. We may use the information you provide in your email to respond to your inquiry, and we reserve the right to retain whatever information you submit in your email, including your name, email address, and any comments or other information that you send via the email mechanism.

Question, Comment, and Feedback Forms

The PSAV Sites may post a form for you to use in submitting questions, comments, and other feedback about us, our affiliates, the PSAV Sites, or our affiliates' products and services, and other topics. We use such feedback information to improve the PSAV Sites, and affiliates' products and services as well as for marketing and research purposes. Most information you provide in such forms is optional, but you will need to provide at least some personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email address, and phone number, so that we may respond to your inquiry.

##### Information Request Forms

The PSAV Sites may include a form that you can use to request information about us, our affiliates, or our affiliates' products and services, or to request catalogs or brochures or price quotes. In addition to asking you to identify the specific information or materials in which you are interested, these forms may request, among other things, your name, phone number, mailing address, and email address, so that we may send you the information or materials you request. These forms may also request certain demographic information about you to help us better understand your interests and needs.

##### Surveys and Evaluations

The PSAV Sites may ask you to complete optional surveys and evaluations about us, our affiliates, the PSAV Sites, or our affiliates' products and services, and other topics. These surveys and evaluations might request personally identifiable information, such as your name and email address, so that we can follow up with you. Typically, we use such surveys and evaluations to better understand our customers and their preferences.

##### Registration Forms

Because access to portions of this Site is restricted to authorized users, you may be required to complete a registration form. This form may ask you for a variety of information that will help us to identify you and contact you, such as your name, business address, office email address, office phone number, and your relationship to us. Registration information will be associated with your username and password, without which you will not be able to access the restricted portions of the PSAV Sites.

#### Passive Information Collection

The PSAV Sites uses various technologies to passively collect information from you while you are visiting (that is, you do not actively provide this information). Such technologies allow the PSAV Sites to collect a range of non-personally identifiable information, including your Internet Protocol (IP) address (a unique identifier automatically assigned to your computer when logging onto the Internet), the type of Web browser and operating system you use, the date and time you visit the Site, the specific pages you visit on the Site, and the address of the Web site you visited before coming to this Site. We typically use such passively collected information for a variety of purposes, such as to administer the Site, customize the Site to your preferences, and compile aggregated statistics for marketing and research purposes. We reserve the unrestricted right to use this passively collected, non-personally identifiable information, including, but not limited to, selling, leasing, permitting access to, or otherwise transferring it to our affiliates, business partners, advertisers, dealers, and other third parties.

Two types of passive information collection technologies deserve special mention:

##### _Cookies_

"Cookies" are small text files that store information about your interactions with a particular Web site, either temporarily (known as a "temporary" or "session" cookie, and deleted once you close your browser window) or more permanently on the hard drive of your computer (known as a "permanent" or "persistent cookie"). Cookies can make it easier to use a Web site by allowing servers to access certain information quickly:

  * Session cookies can be used to help a user's browser navigate a Web site more smoothly and may show up if the user comes from a Web site with which the subsequent Web site has some relationship (e.g., a Web site of an affiliated company) and can give helpful information. 
  * Persistent cookies can be used to customize a Web site for a user, such as by storing passwords, preferences, and registration and account information so that users do not have to reenter them each time they visit a Web site.

This Site uses both session/temporary cookies and persistent/permanent cookies to store information that allows us to offer you better customer service and to navigate through the Site with ease. To make the Site easier to use, we combine information collected via cookies with personally identifiable information. Note that if you configure your browser to reject cookies, you might not be able to access important functions or areas of the Site or enjoy certain conveniences at this Site.

Other Uses and Disclosures of Information

As indicated above, we use information we collect from you via this Site for a variety of purposes. Unless otherwise provided above, we may also use personally and non-personally identifiable information you submit via the PSAV Sites in the following ways:

  * to conduct internal marketing and research; and
  * to improve the content of the Site. 

From time to time, our service providers may have access to information you submit via the PSAV Sites to provide operational or other support services for the PSAV Sites (e.g., Web hosting or database services). We have put in place agreements with such service providers to protect against unauthorized uses or disclosures of such information.

Except as otherwise provided in the "Active Information Collection" section above, we also reserve the right to sell, lease, provide access, or otherwise transfer personally identifiable information you submit via the PSAV Sites to our business partners (including email delivery services and content providers), affiliates, and dealers for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy or elsewhere on the PSAV Sites, we reserve the right to share or transfer any information you submit via the PSAV Sites to another person or company in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of the PSAV Sites and/or PSAV Presentation Services; to respond to law enforcement requests; or where required by applicable law, statute, regulation, ordinance, subpoena, or court order. By submitting personally identifiable information via the PSAV Sites, you consent to such disclosures in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Data Security 

Although we take steps to protect personally identifiable information you provide via the PSAV Sites from loss, misuse, or unauthorized alteration, no system is 100 percent secure or error-free. Therefore, we do not, and cannot, guarantee the security or accuracy of the information we collect via this Site, and you acknowledge that you are assuming the risk in transmitting any information to us.

It is your responsibility to safeguard any usernames and passwords you use to access portions of this Site and to notify us if you ever suspect that these usernames or passwords have been compromised. You acknowledge that you are solely responsible for any unauthorized use of this Site conducted via your username or password.

#### How to Opt Out of Receiving Marketing Materials from PSAV

You can opt-out of our use and disclosure of your PII for marketing purposes and customer satisfaction surveys, and/or withdraw your prior consent for same, by the methods provided below. Your consent will be withdrawn; however, it is possible that you may receive correspondences scheduled prior to our receipt and processing of your opt-out request.

#### _To Opt Out of E-mail Campaigns:_

You may click on the clear “opt out” indicator in promotional or marketing email that you have received from us or you can E-mail us directly at [privacyoffice@psav.com](mailto:privacyoffice@psav.com). Please put the word “Unsubscribe” in the subject line.  If you use more than one email address, then send your opt-out email from each of your email addresses.

#### _To Opt Out of Postal Mail from PSAV and/or our partners:_

You may email us at [privacyoffice@psav.com](mailto:privacyoffice@psav.com) with the words “Opt Out of Postal Mail” in the subject line, or write to us at:

PSAV Presentation Services  
Attn: Privacy Office  
111 West Ocean Boulevard  
Suite 1110  
Long Beach, California 90802   
Phone: 1-562-366-0621  
Fax: 1-562-366-0628  
Email: [privacyoffice@psav.com](mailto:privacyoffice@psav.com)

We may also provide additional methods for you to opt-out of having your PII used or disclosed for promotional and marketing purposes, such as by clicking on a checkbox located on the page of our site on which your PII is collected, or otherwise made available when you make reservations.

Your option not to receive promotional and marketing material: (a) shall not preclude us from corresponding with you, by email or otherwise, regarding your relationship with us (e.g., your account status and activity or our responses to questions or inquiries you pose to us, confirmations for existing reservations); (b) shall not preclude us, including our employees, contractors, agents and other representatives, from accessing and viewing your PII for our internal business purposes; and (c) shall not preclude us from disclosing your PII as described in this Privacy Policy for purposes other than sending you promotional and marketing materials.

If you wish to contact us to: (1) inquire about our privacy practices; (2) provide feedback and comments regarding our privacy practices; or (3) access or correct your PII we have, contact us as detailed above.

#### Ask Us / Enforcement of this Privacy Policy

If at any time you have questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, or the information practices of this Site, please contact us in one of the following ways:

##### _Mail_

PSAV Presentation Services  
Attn: Privacy Office  
111 West Ocean Boulevard, Suite 1110  
Long Beach, California 90802   
Phone: 1-562-366-0621  
Fax: 1-562-366-0628  
Email: [privacyoffice@psav.com](mailto:privacyoffice@psav.com)

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

PSAV reserves the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time so visitors are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy at the inception of each session.

#### Acceptance of this Privacy Policy

By using our Site, or otherwise providing your PII to us, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the PSAV Sites or provide any PII to us.

**This Privacy Policy was last revised on January 1, 2009.**

### Terms of Use

##### Introduction

PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING TERMS OF USE CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS WEB SITE. By using psav.com, or any public Web sites owned/operated by Audio Visual Services Group, Inc. (doing business as PSAV® Presentation Services (“PSAV”)), hereto known as "PSAV Sites," where this policy is displayed, you acknowledge that you have reviewed, and agree to be bound by, the following terms of use. If you do not agree to these terms of use, do not use the PSAV Sites.

#### COPYRIGHT AND TRADEMARK INFORMATION

All textual, graphical, and other content appearing on the PSAV Sites are the property of Audio Visual Services Group, Inc. (doing business as PSAV® Presentation Services) ("we," "our," or "us"), companies partially or wholly owned by Audio Visual Services Group, Inc., or their respective licensors. The Site and all content on the PSAV Sites are provided for lawful purposes only. By accessing and using the PSAV Sites, you agree to abide by U.S. and international copyright law and all other laws applicable to the use of the PSAV Sites.

Procedure for making claims of copyright infringement. In accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (17 USC & 512), PSAV PRESENTATION SERVICES is registered with the US Copyright Office as a Service Provider. Any notifications of claimed copyright infringement must be sent to the Service Provider's Designated Agent.

U.S. Government Restricted Rights. Government users will receive no greater than Restricted Rights as defined in FAR 52.227-19 (c) (1-2) (June 1987). Government users will receive no greater Limited Rights as defined in FAR 52.227-14 (June 1987) or DFAR 252.227-7015 (b) (2) (November 1995), as applicable in any technical data at this site.

#### JURISDICTION

This website is administered by PSAV from its corporate headquarters in the Long Beach, California. This Agreement shall be governed by the laws of the State of California applicable to contracts entered into and performed exclusively in the State of California. Any court of competent jurisdiction sitting within the state of California will be the exclusive jurisdiction and venue for any dispute arising out of or relating to this Agreement. In addition, PSAV makes no representation that materials or services at this website are appropriate or available for use outside the United States, and access to them from territories where their contents are illegal is prohibited. You are solely responsible for insuring compliance with your local laws while using this website and the materials contained in this website. You may not use or export or re-export the materials or services at this website or any copy or adaptation in violation of any applicable laws or regulations including without limitation U.S. export laws and regulations. If you choose to access this website from outside the United States, you do so on your own initiative and are responsible for compliance with applicable local laws.

All brand, product, service and process names appearing on the PSAV Sites are trademarks of their respective holders. Reference to or use of a brand, product, service, or process does not imply recommendation, approval, affiliation, or sponsorship of that brand, product, service, or process by PSAV Presentation Services or its affiliates or subsidiaries. Nothing contained herein shall be construed as conferring, by implication or otherwise, any license or right under any patent, copyright, trademark, or other intellectual property right of ours or any third party, except as expressly granted herein.

All trademarks, service marks, logos and graphics of specific facilities, partners or clients and customers of PSAV contained in this website are the sole property of their respective owners.

#### DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

All content on this Web site is provided “as is” and without warranties of any kind either express or implied. Other than those warranties, which under the U.S. laws applicable to these terms, are implied by law and are incapable of exclusion, restriction, or modification, PSAV disclaims any and all warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. Neither PSAV, its affiliated or related entities, nor the providers, nor any person involved in the creation, production, and distribution of this Web site warrant that the functions contained in this Web site will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that the servers that make the content available will be free of viruses or other harmful components. The content that you access on this Web site is provided solely for your convenience and information only. PSAV does not warrant or make any representations regarding the results that may be obtained from the use of this Web site, or as to the reliability, accuracy or currency or currency of any information content, service and/or merchandise acquired pursuant to your use of this Web site.

You expressly agree that use of this Web site is at your sole risk.  You (and not PSAV) assume the entire cost of all necessary servicing, repair or correction of your system.  You expressly agree that neither PSAV, nor its affiliated or related entities (including its providers), nor any of their respective employees, or agents, nor any person or entity involved in the creation, production and distribution of this Web site, is responsible or liable to any person or entity whatsoever for any loss, damage (whether actual, consequential, punitive or otherwise), injury, claim, liability or other cause of any kind or character whatsoever based upon or resulting from the use or attempted use of this Web site or any other linked site. You expressly acknowledge and agree that PSAV is not liable or responsible for any defamatory, offensive or illegal conduct of other subscribers or third parties. Some jurisdictions may not allow the exclusion or limitation of liability for consequential or incidental damages. In such jurisdictions, PSAV’s liability is limited to the greatest extent permitted by law.

#### LINKS

Within the PSAV Sites, you may see links or references to other Web sites. We undertake no obligation to review the Web sites that may be linked to the PSAV Sites, do not endorse, and are not responsible for the accessibility of, or the resources available on, any other Web sites linked to the PSAV Sites. You are solely responsible for any interactions you may have with such Web sites.

#### SUBMISSIONS

Other than personally identifiable information, which is covered by the PSAV Sites' Privacy Policy, any feedback, data, ideas, comments, suggestions, questions, information, or any other communications ("Submissions") you send via, or post to, the PSAV Sites shall become our exclusive property and shall not be deemed confidential. We shall have no obligation of any kind with respect to such Submissions and shall be free to use and disclose the Submissions to others without limitation. Further, we shall be free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques contained in such Submissions for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to developing, manufacturing and marketing products incorporating such ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques.

#### REVISIONS 

PSAV may revise the terms and conditions of this Agreement at any time by updating this posting. You should visit this page from time to time to review the then-current Agreement because they are binding on you. Certain provisions of this Agreement may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms. A printed version of this Agreement and any notice given in electronic form shall be admissible in judicial proceedings or administrative proceedings based upon or relating to this Agreement to the same extent and subject to the same conditions as other business documents and records originally generated and maintained in printed form. If any term or condition contained in this Agreement is declared unlawful, void or for any reason unenforceable by any court, then any such term will be deemed severable from the remaining terms and will not affect the validity and enforceability of such remaining terms.

#### INDEMNIFICATION

You agree to indemnify, defend, and hold harmless PSAV and the Providers, its and their officers, directors, employees, affiliates, agents, licensors, and suppliers from and against all losses, expenses, damages and costs, including reasonable attorneys' fees, resulting from any violation by you of these Terms.

#### ENTIRE AGREEMENT

The provisions and conditions of these Terms, and each obligation referenced herein, represent the entire Agreement between PSAV, its affiliated or related entities, and you, and supersede any prior agreements or understandings not incorporated herein. In the event that any inconsistencies exist between these Terms and any future published terms of use or understanding, the last published Terms or terms of use or understanding shall prevail.

##### ANY RIGHTS NOT EXPRESSLY GRANTED HEREIN ARE RESERVED BY PSAV
